FLORIAN BÜHLER

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

✓ florian-buehler@outlook.com

in linkedin.com/in/florian-bühler

github.com/florianbuehler

florianbuehler.github.io

KEY SKILLS

FRONTEND DEVELOPMENT

- JavaScript / ES6
- TypeScript
- React.js
- HTML5
- CSS3 / Sass
- Gatsby
- Bootstrap

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT

- C#
- ASP.NET Core
- Node.js
- REST APIs
- Docker
- Postgres

GENERAL

- Docker
- Scrum
- Git / GitHub / GitLab
- Domain-Driven Design
- Test-Driven Design

PROFILE

I am a 29-year-old passionate full stack web developer with a strong handson mentality and over 4 years of experience in building prototypes and web applications from front to back in agile teams. I like to create software to solve real world problems and I strongly believe that anything can be built if it is tackled by a passionate and creative team.

I would describe myself as a person possessing a strong analytical, methodical and problem-solving mindset and with a quick comprehension. I like to get deeply involved in complex challenges and aim to constantly learn new things — especially if it is related to software development and technical innovations. All of these skills and habits have served me well during my five years of mathematical and technical education and in over four years of work as a (senior) consultant and software developer for multiple clients.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR CONSULTANT / WEB DEVELOPER, D-FINE, FRANKFURT

MARCH 2017 - PRESENT

D-fine is a specialized European consulting firm with scientifically minded employees, which provides innovative, customized and futureproof software solutions for complex challenges.

During my time with d-fine I am engaged with requirement gathering, solution design, documentation, coordination with business owners, implementation and testing — mostly in agile setups. Some of the larger projects I have been working on are:

EXTENSION OF A CRYPTO CURRENCY CUSTODIAN

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

Feature implementation and creation of an automated test setup for a highly regulated crypto currency custodian.

The used tech stack includes: JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, C#, ASP.NET Core, REST APIs, Docker, GitLab

EXTENSION OF A MICROSERVICE PLATFORM

JULY 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

Feature implementation of a microservice based platform for a new blockchain related market offering of a big German stock exchange in an agile team.

The project included support in the UI / UX design process and the creation of a fully responsive, cross-browser compatible, modern landing page. A large redesign for the React based frontend, extraction of reusable components into a component library and the creation of an admin dashboard. For the microservices based backend we designed and implemented several new features, accessible through a RESTful application interface and integrated them into the user frontend and the admin dashboard.

FLORIAN BÜHLER

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

LANGUAGES

- German native
- English proficient
- Chinese beginner

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Master

UDEMY CERTIFICATES

- The Web Developer Bootcamp
- Modern HTML & CSS From The Beginning (Including Sass)
- The Git & GitHub Bootcamp
- Understanding TypeScript
- C# Intermediate: Classes, Interfaces and OOP

All changes were automatically tested and continuously integrated into testing environments on AWS and the on-premises live environment through GitLab CI / CD pipelines.

The used tech stack includes: React.js, TypeScript, HTML5, Sass, Gatsby, C#, ASP.NET Core, Postgres, REST APIs, GitLab

DEVELOPMENT OF A MOBILE COUPON PLATFORM

APRIL 2020 - JUNE 2020

Development of a responsive landing page and a mobile first single page application for a coupon platform from front to back in an agile team. Including the setup and configuration of multiple development, a pre-live and a live environment on AWS and GitLab CI / CD pipelines for automated testing and feature deployment.

The used tech stack includes: React.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, Sass, Gatsby, C#, ASP.NET Core, Postgres, REST APIs, GitLab

DEVELOPMENT OF A MICROSERVICE PLATFORM (MVP)

FEBRUARY 2019 - APRIL 2020

Development of a microservice platform MVP for a big German stock exchange in an agile team. The MVP was a prototype for a crypto token emission platform, including user management, project management and the semi-automatic deployment of smart contracts to the blockchain.

The used tech stack includes: React.js, TypeScript, HTML5, Sass, C#, ASP.NET Core, Postgres, REST APIs, GitLab

FEATURE DEVELOPMENT IN A FINANCIAL DATA WAREHOUSE

MARCH 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

Analyzation and feature implementation of customer requirements in a financial data warehouse for a large German universal bank.

MASTER THESIS

Testing new Approaches for the Prediction of Global Stock Markets

BACHELOR THESIS

Efficient Approximation of the Value at Risk in a One-Factor Firm Value Model through Importance Sampling

EDUCATION

ULM UNIVERSITY, DE - M. SC. IN MATHEMATICS AND ECONOMICS

OCTOBER 2014 - NOVEMBER 2016, GRADE "VERY GOOD" (1.3)

Study of mathematics and economics with a focus on optimization, financial modeling and additional programming courses.

MIDDLE EAST TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, TR – ERASMUS SEMESTER

OCTOBER 2015 – JANUARY 2016, GRADE "VERY GOOD" (AA)

ULM UNIVERSITY, DE - B. SC. IN MATHEMATICS AND ECONOMICS

OCTOBER 2011 – JULY 2014, GRADE "VERY GOOD" (1.5)

Study of mathematics and economics with a focus on stochastic, financial mathematics and software development.

During my bachelor studies I was doing an internship with ZEB Consulting, Münster. I was migrating several financial models from MATLAB to F# and created a custom Excel add-in to increase the usability and performance.